And, this is how you perform Kung Fu sparing technique hook block side kick versus side kick.
Now, the hook block is used dropping the arm just like this.
As you do this technique, you're going to actually step to the side to get out of the way.
You're going to hook block and lift the leg up and then drive the technique into the solar plexus.
So, here's one slow so you can see it.
It's one, two.
One done a little faster.
One, two.
The way it looks with an opponent, they're going to do a left leg side kick and you're actually going to parry to the inside of their body.
They slide up and kick, you're going to block hooking with the palm.
Blocking more with the forearm.
Pick the foot up and drive the kick into the solar plexus.
Do one more.
One, two.
From another angle, so you can see.
Switch your feet.
Slide up.
One, two.
Just like that.
Switch feet.
One slow.
One a little faster.
Just like that.
Now, again this technique takes a little bit of timing.
You don't want to dodge too far to the left and you don't want to dodge too far forward.
So, it takes a little bit of practice to get what your natural distance will be.
Again, my name is Wes Rhodes.
I'm from the Chinese Kung Fu Academy.
And, that is how you perform the hook block side kick versus side kick.